

My Contact

- meerraju7074@gmail.com
- +91 7074511827
- Anantapur, Purba Medinipur ,West Bengal-721653
- https://www.linkedin.com/in/ raju-meer

Hard Skill

- Solidworks
- Basic Python
- Aerodynamices
- Microsoft Office
- Hardware Integration
- Aircraft Systems

Soft Skill

- Project Management
- Decision making
- Communication
- Multi-tasking
- Leadership
- Creativity

Education Background

- B.E in AERONAUTICAL ENGINEERING ANNA UNIVERSITY (2019 - 2023) With 8.2 CGPA
- HIGHER SECONDARY (10+2)
 CHANSERPUR HIGH SCHOOL (WBCHSE)
 With 61%
- MADHYAMIK (10TH)

 CHANSERPUR HIGH SCHOOL (WBBSE) With 71%

Hobbies

- Watching Movie
- Travelling
- Cryptocurrency

RAJU MEER

Drone Integration Engineer

About Me

As a UAV Integration Engineer focusing on drone technology, my key areas of expertise include the integration, testing, and optimization of unmanned aerial systems. Additionally, I have extensive proficiency in K++, Pixhawk/Ardupilot-based flight controllers, and mission planners such as Qgroundcontrol. My passion for innovation and analytical acuity enables me to make valuable contributions to the progress of the Aerospace industry.

Professional Experience

Techeagle Innovations Pvt. Ltd. | UAV Systems Engineer Jan 2024 - Present

Key responsibilities:

- Developing, integrating, and validating UAV systems to ensure smooth coordination of diverse elements including sensors, communication systems, flight controls, and payloads.
- Testing the UAV's autonomous capabilities, such as waypoint navigation, obstacle avoidance, and autonomous decisionmaking.
- Evaluating the UAV's performance under various conditions, such as speed, altitude, payload capacity, and endurance.

Oxygen 2 Innovation Pvt. Ltd. | UAV Integration Engineer May 2023 - Dec2023

Key responsibilities:

- Designing, implementing, and testing UAV systems to ensure seamless integration of various components such as sensors, communication systems, flight control systems, and payloads.
- Hardware and Software Integration, Testing and Validation, Troubleshooting and Issue Resolution, Documentation, Research and Development, Project Management and Communication, Continuous Improvement.

GARUDA AEROSPACE PVT. LTD. | Drone Co-Pilot

Dec 2022 - April 2023

Key responsibilities:

- Planning and undertaking scheduled assembly & maintenance of drones.
- Manufacture, assembly, repair & maintenance of drones.
- Pilot for small category drones, Assisting the pilot and preparation, Pre-flight checks, Monitoring flight operations.

Project Undertaken

- Worked as a Intern in a Industrial project "Surveillance and Inspection Micro Quadcopter Drone in Agriculture".
- Participating In the National Level Contest "Model Aircraft Design Challengel.O".
- Worked as a Co-Pilot in "JSW Pipe line inspection Project".
- Work on Aimed at Developing technology for a "Swarm to Detect Foreign Objects on Aircraft Operating Surfaces" in Mehar Baba Competition at BKT Airforce.
- Work on "Drone Detection System" at 9 Base Repair Depot, Indian Airforce in Pune.